<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Derry Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://derry.club/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Derry Dev Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://derry.club/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://derry.club/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 17:32:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://derry.club/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Cheat sheet, a general cheat sheet for all use case</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/docker-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 17:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/docker-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Docker general Help - docker COMMAND --help This is for each command&amp;rsquo;s detail
For example, docker run --help
TL;DR docker run &amp;lt;image&amp;gt; - to initialize a new container docker start &amp;lt;container_name&amp;gt; start running the &amp;ldquo;stopped&amp;rdquo; container docker stop &amp;lt;container_name&amp;gt; docker run - Initialize a container Run a command in a new container
Usage: docker run [OPTIONS] IMAGE [COMMAND] [ARG...]
Basic form to initialize a container, or to run a command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot Controller Service Repository</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/java/spring-boot-controller-service-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 16:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/java/spring-boot-controller-service-repository/</guid>
      <description>Spring RESTful service Laur Spilca Youtube Tutorial series
spring docs
Spring Restful service is a popular backend application. The architecture usually is made up with 3 layers: Controller, Service, and Repository.
Configuration setup @SpringBootApplication - define the app root The start point of program It&amp;rsquo;s with @ComponentScan - tell spring to create beans in which the classes have been annotated with. Spring RESTful Service architecture Spring RESTful service usually has this architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curl cheat sheet, for web developement</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 20:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/curl/</guid>
      <description>HTTP Request Specify Method by -X Form:
curl -X &amp;lt;METHOD&amp;gt; &amp;lt;URI&amp;gt; By default, it uses GET method
curl https://www.google.com/ # same as curl -X GET https://www.google.com/ Use Post simply by:
curl -X POST https://www.example.com/ GET Get entire document of the website in terminal
curl https://www.google.com/ POST curl -X POST https://example.com/ More complex, pass data, -d and header -H to server. Below shows POST with json body
curl -d &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;option&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;value&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;something&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;anothervalue&amp;#34;}&amp;#39; \ -H &amp;#34;Content-Type: application/json&amp;#34; \ -X POST https://example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Abstract Class and how to use it? When we combine it with interface?</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/java/abstract-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 08:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/java/abstract-class/</guid>
      <description>Java abstract class An abstract class is like a structure of data. However, unlike interface, it can define methods and attribute. You can view it as an enforced blueprint for an object. You cannot initiate an object from it but from its sub-classes.
An abstract class is:
It cannot be instantiated It can contain constructor and object fields. Contains abstract method (0 to many), and concrete methods Its subclasses must override its abstract method An abstract class example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java IO package - What is RandomAccessFile and how to use it</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/java/randomaccessfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 18:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/java/randomaccessfile/</guid>
      <description>RandomAccessFile This allows you to read from it or write to it as you please. You can replace the content of the file. This cannot achieve by FileInputStream or FileOutputStream.
Create a RandomAccessFile object RandomAccessFile file = new RandomAccessFile(&amp;#34;file.txt&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;rw&amp;#34;); Mode Description r Read mode. Calling write methods will result in an IOException. rw Read and write mode rwd Read and write mode - synchronously. All updates to file content is written to the disk synchronously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Discussion of AI] Despite the ethical regulations upon AI, Chinese government prioritize the nation welfare in compared to western counterparts</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/despite_the_ethical_regulations_china_prioritize_welfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 20:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/despite_the_ethical_regulations_china_prioritize_welfare/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Artificial Intelligence and its sub-category Machine Learning has gradually taken control of modern civilization. Regulations and mandatory rules are imposed across the globe. The concerns of personal information and privacy has led to the formation of General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in 2018 and identical regulations in United States. As AI algorithms evolves, the more complex and thorough refinement of laws are being imposed [1]. However, in contrast to GDPR and United States, China government emphasizes its nation welfare as priority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git - What Is Origin in Git Push Origin Main</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/git-what-is-origin-in-git-push-origin-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 18:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/git-what-is-origin-in-git-push-origin-main/</guid>
      <description>What is origin in git push origin main? The origin is a convention. It&amp;rsquo;s an alias, short for what we see from the output of git remote -v. You can name it whatever you want. You can think of it as where this code is &amp;ldquo;originated&amp;rdquo; from.
git remote -v # output origin	git@github.com:derrykid/workongit.git (fetch) origin	git@github.com:derrykid/workongit.git (push) Set the remote URL as origin and upstream Whenever we pull the code from remote repository, it flows downstream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git - How to Switch From Password Prompt to Ssh</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/git-how-to-switch-from-password-prompt-to-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 18:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/git-how-to-switch-from-password-prompt-to-ssh/</guid>
      <description>GitHub has terminated the login from password in command line. You can switch to SSH. This tutorial will guide you how to do it.
Git switch from password to SSH What I do is switch remote URLs from HTTPS to SSH. By doing this, the password prompt is no longer there and I can push directly.
Usually we use git clone https://github.com/USERNAME/repo.git to get the clone the remote repo to local machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Archive and Compress Command Tar Gzip</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/linux-archive-and-compress-command-tar-gzip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 20:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/linux-archive-and-compress-command-tar-gzip/</guid>
      <description>Archive vs compress As a former Windows user, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much knowledge about file archiving and file compression. Like most PC users do, I simply collect the files we want to compress and right click the folder to compress then. The output compressed files are, without a doubt, mostly likely to be extension .zip or .rar files. However, when I switch to Linux, things changed. As on the road of knowing more commands, we inevitably go across files extensions ending like .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/git-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:47:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/git-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>I learn git from this interactive tutorial. I take note along the way while I was doing it.
Learn git visual
Commit to repo We was on C1 commit
git commit Branch new branch git branch &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; change branch git checkout &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; create a new branch and check it out It can be shorthand:
git checkout -b &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; merge Now we are working on main branch
We are going to merge the branch bugFix into main</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java - static Keyword</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/java/static-keyword/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 14:30:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/java/static-keyword/</guid>
      <description>static In simple words: static means the variable or methods that assigned to are belonging to the class, not the object. Therefore, there&amp;rsquo;s only one copy of the variable/method in the memory.
When create an object where all instance variables aren&amp;rsquo;t static, every object will own its memory space, and its own copy of value.
Suppose we have a ball class:
class Ball{ double radius; final double PI = 3.14159; } We create 2 Ball objects, each Ball object will have its own instance variables in the memory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys in Database</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/keys-in-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 14:26:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/keys-in-database/</guid>
      <description>There are 8 types of keys in DBMS(Database Management system). Keys are used to help developers to identify a row in a relation(table). Understanding each keys will help you understand and develop a database.
In modern world, data is growing at a rapid pace. So does the demand for professional data analyst. In this article, I will help you understand the keys in DBMS. I suggest you have memorize these terms as it will help you build a logical database and if later on you want to expand the program, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to start over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Format Flash Drive</title>
      <link>https://derry.club/posts/how-to-format-flash-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 12:06:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derry.club/posts/how-to-format-flash-drive/</guid>
      <description>How to format USB (flash drive) in Linux command line? Flash drives are very commonly used. From time to time, we stored our files, presentations, logs in this drives. It&amp;rsquo;s a convenient way to copy and carry around. Sometimes, we&amp;rsquo;ll like to reformat a flash drive, either to use a different file system or to clean up for friend.
In Linux, there are several graphic software that provides you the same ability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
